<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux on Thomas J. Petz, Jr.</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux on Thomas J. Petz, Jr.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 10:25:17 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Recover Synology rsync backup jobs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/synologyrecovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 10:25:17 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/synologyrecovery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently upgraded a very old Netgear ReadyNAS device to a new Synology DS-420+ at a remote location.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The main use of the old ReadyNAS was an a rsync target for backing up my main Synology rack station.  I have about 2.5TB of rsync’d files.  I wanted to reuse the existing rsync files to avoid the several months necessary to build a new  backup.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I thought I could just repoint the existing Hyper Backup jobs on the Synology rack station.  This did not work as I couldn’t reset the name of the share where the files were to be backed up to.  I also tried building new jobs using the targets of the copied files but this would error out because HyperBackup would report that files already existed in the target directories.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resolution on Bind9 on NFS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/bind9onnfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 10:26:49 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/bind9onnfs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After a good bit of investigation and thinking… the problem with bind9 has nothing to do with bind9. The problem was a mismatch between UIDs between the Synology NAS server and the bind account on the pi. As I was using sec=sys for authentication all the authentication is based on UIDs. On the pi bind has a UID of 109. There was no account on my Synology NAS with a UIDs of 109. Hence the access was denied by the NFS server.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trouble with Bind9 on a Pi with NFS root</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/troublewithbind9onnfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 10:29:24 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/troublewithbind9onnfs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I got a new Raspberry Pi 4 as I’m looking to consolidate some of my old Pi’s and clean up my servers. To avoid issues with wearing out the SD cards I mount the root file system off an NFS NAS storage server.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately I’ve hit a problem with installing Bind9 using the defaults when mounting root via NFS. When starting Bind9 I get the error&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;named[5466]: working directory ‘/var/cache/bind’ is not writable&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
