<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nano33 on Thomas J. Petz, Jr.</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/nano33/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nano33 on Thomas J. Petz, Jr.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 17:50:01 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/nano33/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>SWD Breakout and Breadboard for Nano 33 BLE Sense</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/nanobreakout/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 17:50:01 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/nanobreakout/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Arduino Nano 33 BLE (Sense) and the Nano 33 IoT expose SWD pads on the bottom of the board.  These pads expose the SWD interface that enable debugging when used with an SWD compatible debugger such as the Segger &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.segger.com/products/debug-probes/j-link/models/j-link-edu-mini/&#34;&gt;J-Link Mini EDU&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The pads on the bottom of the Nanos are very small (and as we’ll see later quite fragile).  Normally you would use some form of test fixture and pogo pins to connect to the pads.  I don’t have that.  Some approaches show soldering dupont wires to the pads and then connecting to the J-Link via and adapter.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Arduino Project</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/newarduinoproject/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2019 10:33:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/newarduinoproject/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m working on tracking down and resolving a humidity problem in our home. While I have some basic measurements of humidity through our Nest Thermostat and a Canary device I want broader coverage so I can measure localized problem areas. The relatively new Arduino 33 BLE Sense looks to be a great device to meet my needs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’m creating a simple network combining BLE (Bluetooth Low Energy) and WiFi. I’m planning to use an Arduino 33 BLE Sense to measure the environment. the Arduino 33 BLE Sense doesn’t have Wifi. I’m planning to use an Arduino 33 IoT to act as a “gateway”, polling the Sense for measurements and periodically publishing them to an MQTT broker. The MQTT broker will be Mosquitto running on a Raspberry Pi.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
